Hello, it's story time. It is story time. It is story time because I want to talk about
care. I want to talk about spaces for care. And I want to talk about
the fact that customer service is not about you dealing with a customer,
but it's about an interpersonal exchange. And I want to talk about an experience that I recently
had at the YMCA. So I don't know if you all know this, but the YMCA is a nonprofit community
organization. It's a place where people are supposed to be able to come to get, you know,
access to workout equipment, to swimming pools, to classes for a reasonable amount of money.
And I also want to say that though I am going to share a story of folks not showing up,
it was happening in the midst of other folks showing up. And I don't want to disregard those
people and I don't want to leave them for last. I want to acknowledge first Katina and Joanne
because they were very actively welcoming me into that space. And I think it's really important
to acknowledge the folks who do that, right? Because particularly in spaces where you're coming
to release places that you're coming for community, you want those people in those spaces to show up
in a certain way. I'm really enjoying swimming at the YMCA because the water is a very regulatory space
for me. And as I continue my growth and my healing, I understand that it is imperative that I make very
deliberate efforts to stay regulated. I am a hypersensitive person due to my empathic nature and
being autistic. And so I really do have to be very thoughtful about how I manage myself.
Um, I think it's also important. This person said, we're calling out an underpaid and overworked
worker. And I think that it's really odd to make that statement before I have even said what I've said.
I think it's also pretty problematic to suggest that being overworked and underpaid
somehow is a reason for just being, um, nasty. Yeah. Um, because some of the most kind
periods, sorry, sorry. Some of the most kind, um, thoughtful people are underworked and overpaid.
Rest in peace to me. I mean, sorry, overworked and underpaid. Rest in peace to Miss Shirley
Raines. And if anybody's ever been to Walmart, you know, Walmart has some of the kindest people ever.
Okay.
You know, I'm not saying that people are not tired. I'm not saying that people
are not, um, frustrated, but I do think it's important to understand that as we continue
to be, um, as we continue to be a changing society, we're going to consistently have to check
ourselves in how we have accepted practices of, um, disregard for each other. And we have to
acknowledge that when we accept that we are now indoctrinating ourselves into the colonization.
We're, we're, we're literally saying, well, I'm going to be a low vibrational person because
the system has made me that way. And there's just way too many examples of folks who have gone other
directions to suggest that that has to be a bottom, bottom line, baseline reaction. I have been swimming
at this YMCA for a year and it has been lovely. Y'all, I'm in there in my long sleeve bathing suits.
I'm sharing the lanes with people named like Morty and Saul. Um, I'm swimming and talking to myself
and regulating and it's just been a really great addition to my self-care practice. Right. Um,
and it allows me to feel more restored in how I can show up in my other, um, in, in, in,
in my outward care practice. Right. So there's like self-care practice and then there's outward
care practice. You got to take care of the self so that you can take care of the community.
So I was really, really enjoying that. And, um, it was essentially the same scenario every time I
would go, you know, there might be two or three people there. The pool only has two lanes. Um,
and so you end up maybe sharing with folks, which is no problem. Um, and oh my gosh, I didn't say that
Sarah. Um, and announce myself. My bad. Um, I had just finished yoga. I was a little spacey. So
basically I was, I'm still down by the way. Um, and so I say all that to say that it was a very
dope experience. And the way it's laid out is there's two, there's two lanes. Then there's a
hot tub and a sauna. One day about a couple, maybe two months ago, um, two, three months ago,
there was a different lifeguard on duty and he would pace around the pool continuously during the swim.
Um, um, which I had never experienced from any lifeguard there prior. And the pacing around the pool
while I was swimming was giving me anxiety. It was incredibly distracting and it just felt like I was
being like stalked. Um, and because it's a small pool, it's not like there's, um, like spaces of time.
It's literally just like someone circling you like then, then, then, and he's walking quickly. Right.
So it's, it's not like he's just like sauntering, you know, he's like, like I demonstrated this on
Patreon. It's like you're swimming in the person's like, I was accustomed to, and I know someone here
is being a smart ass and says just like lifeguarding. And, you know, I think that that's interesting
because I had been swimming there for a year and had never experienced that. So to suggest that all
of a sudden, Hey Spice, um, to suggest all of a sudden like, Oh, that's just the protocol. It's
like, well, maybe that is the protocol, but that has not been the protocol that has been presented
up until this point. Um, that's, what's up gotta be me. So, um, when he, when he came to the, to he,
well, in his middle of, of pacing, I said to him, you know, your, your pacing is very, it's very
disruptive. And his response was, I'm just doing my job. Um, I love how there's like all these people
in here. Like maybe he's uncomfortable sitting or he has a tick. None of that has anything to do
with the situation. Like, um, I'm telling you, like, you know, like I'm not telling you the story
for you to diagnose him. Not, not, none of that is necessary for any part of this. Um,
so to be quite honest, um, that's irrelevant. So when he said, I'm just doing my job, that is an
immediate invalidation of somebody's experience. There is a lifeguard chair. Yes. And typically
the lifeguard that I've experienced is sitting in the lifeguard chair, holding his lifeguard thing.
And there's only two lanes in the pool. And so he is able to, you know, assess what's going on in
the pool. Um, while you're, while you're there and this person, ordinary, brilliant, 861, thank you
for pointing this out. They said, everyone seems to be used to suppressing their own comfort for other
people and not advocating for themselves. And I want you guys to remember that concept.
So now, um, when he says, I'm just doing my job, I said, well, that's not really like a
practical or useful response to what I've suggested, to what I've said. Like that really is
very dismissive. He said, if you have a problem, you can take it up with my boss.
Cool, cool, cool, cool, cool, cool. So this young man could not have been, I don't know. I don't
think he's more than 21. Um, he had very sculpted eyebrows and I'm not sure if he was Latino or Arab.
Um, but I had never, uh, been in the pool while he was there before. So now, um, I go into
the locker room and when I come out of the locker room, um, he is talking to his boss and he says,
oh, speak of the devil. How people in here are like making statements like the lifeguards at the YMCA
do X, Y, Z. And I, I find it fascinating because I am actively telling you that I have been there for
a year and no other lifeguard has done that. So I am not sure what the necessity is for you all to
dis and for them, by the way, to, uh, disregard my experience, but I do not appreciate it and it is not
useful. Okay. So when this man says, speak of the devil, I said, oh, so I'm the devil now and
white, because I'm an angel. So I went to my car and I was going to leave. Um, and I said, you know,
I need to address this. And the reason it needs to be addressed is because of what, uh, the person
whose name started with brilliant said before you have to advocate for yourself. I am not saying
that I don't like the pacing because I don't like his legs. I'm not saying I don't like the pacing
because, um, um, I, it's a preference. I'm saying it because I'm getting anxiety. Now this person here
just literally said to me, it's a figure of speech because he was talking about you to his employer.
Twilight Zone 1981. I was born in 1981. Do you think that I do not know that speak of the devil
is a figure of speech? Do you honestly think that I don't know that? Words have meaning.
If someone says speak of the devil and you are the devil, they're still calling you the devil.
Y'all have become so comfortable with language that is not meant for high vibration. That is not
meant for live for, for lifting. Okay. And so you continue to use it. It's like the phrase,
kill two birds with one stone. Why are we killing the birds? And mama Zota, thank you for bringing that
to our attention. Is it professional to say things at like that at work? By the way, it's not giving
customer service. If we don't become more intentional with every part of our life, we continue
that control of us that we don't have any consciousness of. Okay. There are so much control
that you can't control. At the very least, you can control yourself. Okay. And I spoke to his,
I guess his supervisor. And the supervisor said, well, you know, these younger guys really don't have
the same level of respect that we do. This was the first thing that was said to me, not let me hear
your side of the story. The first thing that was said to me was that these younger guys have a
different level of respect and that essentially I should basically just chalk it up to that and
basically just disregard what is taking place. So I said, let's stop before we do that. And I want to
tell you the story that took place. I want to share with you my experience. So I gave my experience
and at the end of that, he said, well, listen, you know, um, that, that definitely isn't cool.
It's not cool, but I just got here. I just started working here recently and listen, I've been dealing
with a whole bunch of stuff here. I mean, you know, I just got yelled at the other day for, for,
for sweeping. So, you know, like this environment, you know, is, and I said, brother,
I say this with love. I am not here to learn of your complaints about working here.
I am here to express to you the negative experience that I have had with one of the employees.
And I just want to know that it's going to be addressed. And I would also like to know that
I can be accommodated. And he's like, okay, yes, yes. Um, he said, you know, because I only go there
twice a week to swim for 20 minutes. So he said, yes, we will accommodate you. You know, when you're
here, yes, it is protocol for us to pace around the pool. And I said, you know, you said that a couple
times now, and I just, again, want to bring to your attention that I have been swimming here for a
year. And this is the first day that I've experienced that. So if that is protocol, it has not been what
I've experienced, um, which is why I'm bringing this to your attention. Like I'm not pulling it just
out of nowhere. Um, and, um, he said, no, I understand. So I went along with my day. Um,
um, and I came back and there was the re the previous lifeguard was there. And so for the next
two months, no issues because the same lifeguard that's always there was there sitting in the chair.
So then I went back about two weeks ago and the brother, the brother that was there, the lifeguard,
he is the aquatics director. And, um, I said to him, you know, uh, this nigga Latif, by the way,
he had on a, he had on a camouflage do-rag. So I said, when I was here last time, not last time,
but when I was here prior, uh, this nigga Latif said that I can be accommodated with the no pacing.
So I'm assuming that this has been discussed because you're the head of aquatics.
And he said, yes, that's no problem. And it was no problem. It was no problem.
Have a go on Krishna, Krishna. I swam. Of course he felt the need to say, you know,
it is protocol for us to walk around. I said, I have not experienced that except for one time.
And that was the time I'm referring to. So it was a black and white camouflage do-rag. I just need
to clarify also a black and white camouflage do-rag. So I swam. No problem. Cool.
I came back last week and, um, I was given a heads up that the lifeguard that I had initially had a
negative interaction with was there. And I say, you know what, I'm going to just go. I'm going to
just go. Cause I really didn't want to have that type of interaction. And so I went for a walk with
my dog instead. But to be quite honest, I'm, I'm paying a membership here.
And this is a space of community. And the truth is that when we are understanding of community,
we know that community involves multiple types of people. Community requires
an acknowledgement of individuality. And unfortunately, we live in a world that attempts
to create these templatized homogeneic rule systems that oftentimes leave entire groups of people out.
Ask the disabled community, cause they will tell you.
In our failure to meet people individually within reason, we carry forth the work of colonization.
When you see the crate and barrel pottery barn palette of white, off white and cream, what you're
seeing is a desire to strip the people of the world of their individuality, of their uniqueness,
in order to make them easier to control. It makes them faceless. It makes them drones.
This is why slaves had their master's last name. It renders them inhuman. So in even the smallest
spaces of our lives, we can push back against this by seeing people as individuals.
Right? And I have really come into this as I moved out of LA back to a place that feels more connected
to earth. Because even when you look at the forest, every tree is an individual tree doing its part in
the forest. Yes, there may be a bunch of birch trees. There may be a bunch of oak trees. There may be a bunch
of cedar trees, but each one of those trees comes from a seed and has a story. Okay? So we are the same.
We are the same. Each one of us comes from a seed and has a story. And we are contributing to the forest
forest of us and the forest of this earth. So when we look at each other, we have to see that.
Okay? We have to see that. So when I am in the world, I find myself much, much, much, much, much more
prescient and present in existing in that way. This is why I try my best to compliment people all the time.
This is why I try my best to have interactions with people in the store, not simply transactions
with people in the store. Right? And I think it was, it's also very necessary to be able to communicate
when you can't make accommodations. Right? That's a very important part of working or being anywhere.
Being able to communicate when you can't make accommodations and doing so in a way that
acknowledges the person for their limitations or their needs while also acknowledging the scenario.
Oh, Zach absolutely got blocked. So if someone says this behavior is giving me anxiety,
the word anxiety should trigger you to say, okay, um, how, how can we possibly work together to come
around this? Right? Um, instead I was completely ignored. That was completely, you know what? Sincerely,
Shantae, you're about to get blocked because you keep asking questions as if I have finished the story
and I have not. So just stop, be patient and listen. Like what is, so, and I know I'm not the first
person to tell you that in your life. So now I am, I come back this week and the, after I had come back
and the guy was there that, and I was like, let me just leave. I came back later this week and she,
and the person, someone gave me a heads up and was like, oh, they're here. But I said, you know,
the reality is I should be able to come here and not have to like worry about the lifeguard.
So I'm going to do my swim. So I came in and there was only one person in the pool.
There was only one person in the pool. Thank you, Isabella.mt. And I came to the lifeguard
with the sculpted eyebrows. And I said, you know, last time I was here, when you referred to me as
the devil, I spoke to Lateef and he said that he would accommodate while I'm swimming for my 20
minutes, not pacing. And he said, yeah, it's fine. That's it. I begin my swim. At the last five minutes
of my swim, I see a person standing at the end of the lane. I, three quarters of the way down,
pop out. And I'm like, what's up? Because someone standing at the end of your lane,
if you're swimming is very like imposing. And it is the aquatics director who is standing there
in his bubble coat. And he said, I'm just addressing something with the lifeguard. And I said, oh,
cause you're standing right here. And he said, you know what? So now we're in the pool. I'm in the pool.
There are other people in the pool. And he says, you know what? We can't just make accommodations
for you. There are other people here. We don't, we can't make, we can't just be making accommodations
for you. So I'm going to pause real quick. That is untrue. I want y'all to know that that is untrue.
That is the language of laziness. Accommodations are made all the time for individuals. The thing is,
is that oftentimes those accommodations are made because of how much money someone has
or how many connections that person has. Very often that is why an accommodation is, is made.
It is absolutely possible to make accommodations for individuals. And for what it's worth in a
community space, it is absolutely necessary to consider that you will have to make accommodations
for people. So now he is squatting at the end of my lane that I'm in, in the pool. And I am in the
pool. And he is saying to me, yo, like there's other people here, you know, there's other people
here that are, that are, you know, like that, that's why we have to pace around the pool. Like people
can fall in, et cetera, et cetera. So we need to pace around the pool. And you know, you, and for the
record, like that man, Latif, he don't even work here anymore, but he never told you that. He never
told you that. I said, okay, stop, stop, stop. Because you're now telling me that you're, that I'm
lying. He said, no, because he never said that to you. He wouldn't say that. He wouldn't say that.
And I said, okay, I don't like how you're speaking to me. He said, I'm not speaking to you any kind of
way. I said, yes, you are. You literally just cut me off. He said, no, you cut me off. I said, no,
I stopped you from referring to me as something. I'm not, which is a liar. By the way, I am in the
pool. This is happening in the pool setting. This is a black man. I am a black woman. And this person
is absolutely being wildly, not only disrespectful, but this is also unsafe. And
you have already accommodated me, already been accommodated. So I actually can be accommodated.
So you're sitting, you're literally standing over me, talking to me while I am in the pool,
you know, Jonah Castro and you're gaslighting me. And I said, I have never experienced this
pacing with anybody else. And he said, yes, you have. No, you haven't. I know. He said,
yes, you have. Everybody here paces. So I am literally explaining and being told this did not
take place. And of course I said, are you calling me a liar? And he said, yes, I am calling you.
He didn't say yes. I'm calling you. He said, yes, because he never said that to you. He would never
say that. I got out that pool and you know, I say, you got the right one. You got the right one.
Yes. Trolling black women is a sport because I can promise you he would never speak to any of those
elder white women in there this way ever. I then went and spoke to the members, the woman who's like
the membership liaison person. And she's always been super kind. And so I was talking to her and
just explained to her the situation. I had already explained to her the situation prior to. So she was
already aware of this and she was very like receptive. And she was like, no, that is unacceptable.
Like that is unacceptable. And no, that really isn't how it should be dealt with. And then of
course, what's going to happen? Where my cancer's at? What's going to happen next? I'm going to cry
because you're so filled with so many emotions. Now Z stacks says, why is it so popular to pick on me
or to pick with me? I have what's called a reflective personality. So it's big and it's a mirror. So it's
very easy to be triggered by my presence because I reflect back to you what you don't like about you
and you immediately become defensive. And in spaces with people who are not dealing with that, who are
not lying to themselves, with people who are very secure about themselves, I don't have those problems.
All of us in this world carry different frequencies. We emit different energy signals.
That is my energy signal. I emit, I emit a reflective energy frequency.
So when you're around me, you will see the best parts of yourself that you didn't know you had.
And you'll see the worst parts of yourself that you may have been present, that you may have been
lying about existing. This makes relationships very hard with people who are not in pursuit of healing.
Because when you're in pursuit of healing, the mirror is hella helpful. I was with Pisces. So they
mirrored me while I was mirroring them. But that mirror helped me to heal. It forced me to look at the
ways in which I was carrying out practices that I don't like when people do to me. It forced me
to dig deeper into my trauma that was triggering and that I was using as an excuse to behave a certain
way. That mirror that he was to me forced me to face me and not make everybody else my reason for
things. Some people are your reason for things, but not all the time. And so that's also why my last
relationship had to end because when his mirror reflected me back to me, I got busy.
I got busy in changing. It did not happen in reverse. I'm a water sign. And what does water do,
babe? It reflects. So I'm here in an office at the YMCA crying because, and I said this to Katina,
I said, because it just breaks my heart that we treat each other like this. We don't have to treat
each other like this. We don't have to align ourselves so staunchly to positions of power
that it makes us forget our existence of humanity. There's a real power trip that happens.
And it says to me that we're lacking in real deep ways when we find our power in this.
Because our power should really be coming from a much more organic exchange. I feel power and by
power, I mean energized, right? I feel powered by creating and sharing work that gives you guys
energy, that gives you guys, you know, a feeling of hope, that gives you guys action, right? Like I
feel power by making you laugh, right? Like Michael Che hit me the other day to ask if I still consider
myself a comic. And I said, absolutely, because the ability to make people laugh is a superpower.
Power. That is great. That is leaked. That is literally tapping into the joy space and bringing
it about for somebody. And I've been able to do that in the worst of times. I got in a car accident
in the backwoods of Togo and we had to drive in the back of a pickup truck to a military hospital.
And the two other people were like frightened out of their minds. And then there was a brother that was
laid out in the back of the pickup truck bed, like with a head injury. And I said, I got to make
people laugh. And I was able in that time of really great fear and uncertainty to make people laugh.
And so I know, you know, what that power is. And I believe like the most showing example of love to
someone is being curious about them. So when we're not curious about each other, um, in respectful ways,
of course, we're cutting that empathy off. And what I experienced at the NIAC YMCA was a lack of
empathy, of basic empathy that I should experience as a human, but also of empathy that I should
experience in a community space. And when members of my Patreon contacted them and said, we don't
appreciate how Amanda was treated. They were responded to by the person in charge and told that I had been
told several times that protocol is XYZ and I ignored it. I was also told, and furthermore, that I was
addressing Marcus, the aquatic director, when he wasn't even the lifeguard. That is what was being
responded. That was the response by their boss. I want y'all to know energy comes from the top down.
Energy comes from the top down. I said, cancel my membership because I've seen your emails and it is
clear why your staff, and it is clear by your response, why your staff behaves the way they do. So this
black man is empowering this younger black man who is empowering this younger Latino or Arab person to speak to
people who are members at this YMCA any old type of way, to gaslight, to police, and furthermore, to simply
dismiss and ignore. What should have happened was that that person, particularly about being contacted
several times by people that are advocating for me, should have reached out to me directly, because I did
confirm that he had my phone number, to ask my experience. He should have asked me to come into the space
and to hear my experience and to hear my experience from my mouth and how that exchange took place in my
experience. This is how you show basic civility, basic civility. I wake up every day and show up in the
world to be kind, to be creative, and to find more and more ways to decolonize and to become a community.
I'm bringing soursop tea for the elders around me that have cancer. I'm bringing aid to Cuba this week
when I go with the delegation from IFCO, and I am not simply just talking about it, but being about it.
The reality around these types of spaces is that people really be at work forgetting what their work is,
forgetting why you're there. I have a platform so I can express this frustration. Most people don't.
They end up having to just swallow it and it metastasizes within your cells when you have to
consistently swallow, when you have to consistently suppress and repress. You wonder why it on,
maybe if you're seeing the people of it on and you're seeing how strong they are, I want you to also
look at how they mourn. Release! Release! So I wanted to share that story because I know many of us work
in spaces with other people and sometimes we can forget what that means. And also we live in a world
with other people and it can very easily be forgotten what our responsibility is. We are being ruled by
those who mine our toxic energy to empower themselves. We cannot live in that. We also have to be
adamant about calling it out and about holding people accountable because we get trained to think that if we do
that, we are being a problem. We are being a Karen. We are being disruptive. That is not correct.
Karen's yell lies. Truth tellers disrupt lies by yelling the truth.
So for those of you all, thank you for listening. Um, I think I have found another place where I will be
able to engage in my restorative and my, um, my restorative and my rejuvenative practices.
And, um, you know, the NIAC YMCA has a lot of work to do in how their staff members in the aquatics
part of the, uh, organization are showing up. Um, I was really deeply disappointed that these were
black men specifically that did not give a damn and that were addressing me in such aggression.
Um, and, um, Karen is not a harmful stereotype. Brick Hillian. Shut up. Um, let me just side note
real quick. A Karen is not a stereotype. It's a reality. Karen is actually a very kind way.
It's a very kind way of addressing narcissistic white women who are constantly using their whiteness
to weaponize, who are constantly weaponizing their whiteness. The term Karen is actually very kind.
They're literally violent. Okay. They're, they're actually violent. They're, they're literally terrorists.
So calling them a Karen is actually like a very, very graceful, uh, nomenclature, very generous.
So that's my story. And, um, again, I want to thank Katina and Joanne who are always very kind
at the space. And, um, I just always want to remind us that we have the choice. We have,
we have choices that we make all day long and many of us don't realize how often we are actually
behaving in a way that was designed for us and that we didn't choose for ourselves. And I hope
particularly for that young man that he comes into an age of maturity where he sees the error of his
ways where he sees how he became engrossed in the, um, position of power and chose to project it
on a person who simply just wanted to be able to come there and not feel anxious at a time where
they are choosing to regulate. So, um, we all know that there are very, very, very, very, very,
very serious, violent interactions taking place all over the world, all over the world. And we have
to always hold our candle for those who are in the midst of those interactions. And we who may not
currently be in those interactions have a responsibility to do our part in preventing
them. And the last thing I'll say is this, some might say, well, what do you expect? It's a YMCA.
And I think we have to also remember you should not have to pay more for better treatment. Think about
this. You should not have to pay more for better treatment. There might be more, there might be access
to other facilities. There might be a higher level of luxury. There might be different equipment,
but on a basic level, you should not have to pay more to be treated kindly. I was on a flight once
and there was only one bathroom working at the back of the plane. I was in first and there was a
bathroom in first. A woman had a baby and was asking, you know, can she bring the baby to the
bathroom in first? Because the bathroom in the back of the plane, the one that was the only one
that was open was actually like being in use for a long time. And do you know the flight attendant said
no? And I said, you know, I don't think anybody here in first class gives a rat's ass if someone uses
that bathroom knowing that there are not two bathrooms in the back. No one argued the point.
She was able to use the bathroom. I was on a flight recently and we were sitting on the tarmac
and they were like, well, we don't know when we're going to take off. And there was no air conditioning.
Again, I was in first and there was, it was a, it was like a, a, one of those like puddle jumper
planes basically. But there was only like four people in the back. Okay, sweet Judy pie. You
clearly don't fly often. I want to see somebody just go for it. The first class cabin, the first
class bathroom is literally by the cockpit. You trying to get people killed? Don't give bad advice.
So the flight attendant comes and gives the three people in first class water and a snack
and ignores the three people in the back. Gives them water. Oh, well, that's the, that's the
responsibility of the flight attendant in the back. Can you please contact him? Because why do they not
have water? It is hot, sweltering on this plane. You're going to have a health case.
They got water. Make a choice today to expand your perspective and your peripheral beyond yourself
and see what you come up with. You might spot somebody who needs help that you didn't know
needed help. You might somebody, you might spot somebody that's looking fly as hell and you get
to enjoy the whimsy of their finest and let them know. So I also encourage you to expand
your peripheral to take in the glory of my sweater. Amanda, are those people on a canoe
in the Amazon? Why, yes. Yes, they are. Enjoy the rest of your day, y'all.